原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译:  冰蓝  亲爱的小饭  斑驳  洗七里
翻译:  ET外星人  油腻希  戳穿鬼话赛太公
校对:  新浪微博@赛太公
时间轴:  三水
后期:  瓜瓜    总监： 怀念浓子的瓜瓜
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    美剧炸了
了解最新影视资讯字幕信息
摩  登
家  庭
第九季 第四集
真想知道曼尼现在在做什么
I wonder what Manny's doing right now.
你给他打个电话吧
Why don't you call him?
你打啊  我又不在乎他在做什么
You call him. I don't care what he's doing.
我在尽量不烦他
I'm trying not to bug him.
他说他需要一些时间来适应大学
He said that he needed some time to adjust to college,
所以我在给他
so I'm giving him --
停车
Stop the car!
你为什么要这样
Why would you do that?!
那好像是小短
I think that's Shorty.
从我开始记事
Shorty and I have been best friends
小短就是我最好的朋友
for as long as I can remember.
他和他老婆达琳几年前
He and his wife, Darlene, moved to Costa Rica
搬去了哥斯达黎加  原因是...
a few years back for, uh --
我不知道
I don't know why.
吃豆子  抵抗疟疾  喝人们的洗澡水
Ruin his life eating beans, fighting malaria,
以此毁掉自己的生活吗
drinking water people bathe in?
这种时候
This.
你这种时候就听起来像有种族歧视
This is when you sound racist!
你回来都不告诉我的吗
You come to town and you don't tell me?
看老子不掐死你
I ought to punch you in the neck,
你这个王八蛋
you son of a bitch.
杰
Jay!
我要踢你的膝盖
I want to kick you in the knee,
你这个蠢蛋
you stupid idiot!
没这种说法
That might not be a thing.
你是个很垃圾的最好的朋友
You're a terrible best friend.
别冲我吼  我才回来几天
Don't yell at me. I'm only here a couple of days.
临时决定回来  本来有要打给你
It was last-minute. I was gonna call.
这是乔吗
This Joe?
你真大
You're huge.
我还能长更大
Eh, I can be bigger.
你干什么呢  住哪里
What are you doing? Where are you staying?
我住那边的酒店
I'm checking in at the hotel over there.
不能住酒店
No hotels.
你乱花钱  就跟乱穿裤子一样
You're as bad with money as you are with pants.
你穿的这是什么鬼
What's going on down there, anyway?
这裤子吗
These?
松身裤
Palazzos.
从未感觉如此舒适
Never felt so comfortable.
随心所欲  毫无阻碍
Everything goes where it wants to go.
小短  不如你来住我们家吧
Shorty, why don't you come and stay with us?
你还能有自己的房间呢
You will even get your own room
因为曼尼去上大学了
'cause Manny's off to college.
上大学  他怎么样了
College?! How's he doing?
真希望我知道  他需要一些空间
I wish I knew. He needed some space.
在此期间
In the meantime,
她给他寄了个菲亚特汽车那么大的补给包
she sends him a care package the size of a Fiat,
里面还装着一包我最爱的香肠
which included a pack of my favorite sausage.
我没把香肠放...
I did not put the sausage --
不然香肠去哪儿了  我吃没吃我心里有数
Well, where did it go, then?! I know what I ate!
我现在有太多烦心事了
There's too many things upsetting me right now.
快去拿你的行李
Go get your stuff.
来我们家碰头  说定了
Meet us back at the house. It's done.
-没问题  -真棒
- You got it! ‭- Yes!
曼尼走了后  家里终于
It's gonna be so nice since Manny's gone
又有个有趣的人  真是太好了
to have somebody fun again in the house.
你准备好了吗  大哥哥
Are you ready for this, big boy?
我准备好了
Oh, I'm ready.
场面会很乱的
And it's gonna get pretty messy.
你想要当蓝色还是金色
So, do you want to be blue or gold?
当蓝色
I'll be blue.
因为我很酷...
'Cause I'm cool --
好痒
Aah! That tickles!
克莱尔最近去了个单身女郎派对
Claire recently went to a bachelorette party
他们送了每个人激情绘画工具
where they gave everyone a passion painting kit.
这个就是让你和你伴侣
The idea is that you and your partner
将身上涂满颜料
cover one another in paint --
趴在画布上
get down on the canvas.
然后"好好作画"
And then get down on the canvas.
别扭来扭去了  菲尔
‭Stop squirming, Phil.
我都没法给你涂颜料了
I'm never gonna get this paint on you.
好吧  我给你涂
Okay, I'll do you.
把你变成金色  就像奥斯卡小金人
You're gonna be so gold, you'll like an Oscar.
-有好多人要感谢呢  -是啊
- So many people to thank. ‭- Oh, yeah.
糟糕  是艾丽克斯
Oh, crap, it's Alex.
别接啊
Just ignore it.
不行  万一是出了什么事怎么办
I can't. What if something's wrong?
亲爱的  一切还好吗
Hi, honey. Everything okay?
是啊  我只是想告诉你
Yeah, I'm just, uh, letting you know
今晚我会家睡
I'm sleeping at home tonight.
你还有多久到
Uh, h-how far away are you?
大概二十分钟
About 20 minutes.
那我们有十分钟的时间清理
Oh, that leaves 10 minutes for cleanup.
还有  本今晚可以住家里吗
Also, is it okay if, um, Ben stays over tonight?
行啊  他妈咪同意就行
Sure. I guess if his mommy says it's okay.
妈  你没必要每次本来我们家
Mom, you don't have to take a shot at Ben
都要嘲笑他一次吧
every time he comes up.
就是嘛  我怎么可能没先问过我妈同意
Yeah, right, like I wouldn't ask my mom.
我真的该装作没听见吗
I'm really supposed to ignore that?
听着  他是我男朋友
Listen, he is my boyfriend,
-我真的要受够了  -冷静点
- and I'm getting really tired of this. - Oh, calm down.
-只是开玩笑啊  -一点都不好笑
- It was just a joke. - Well, it's not funny!
你攻击本  就等于攻击我
When you attack Ben, you attack me.
好了好了  我知道了
Yeah, yeah, I got it.
我们进行到哪儿了
Now, where were we?
亲爱的  我好像没感觉了现在
Honey, I kind of think maybe the moment has passed.
是我爸  又怎么了
Ohh, it's my dad. What now?
别接啊
Just ignore it.
不行  万一是出了什么事怎么办
I can't. What if something's wrong?
-亲爱的  -嗨  老爸
- Hey, honey. - ‭Hi, Dad.
小短来了
Shorty's in town!
我要我送给菲尔的那套高尔夫球杆
I need that set of golf clubs I gave to Phil.
反正给那笨蛋也只是浪费那套杆子
That bonehead's certainly not putting them to any good use.
为什么  老爸  你为什么老攻击他
Why, Dad? Why do you always have to attack him?
冷静点  只是开个玩笑啊
Oh, calm down. It was just a joke.
我明早来取
I'll pick them up in the morning.
我会被他气死
He pisses me off so much!
来吧  接着玩
Come on! Let's do this!
感觉你玩的目的不是因为我了
This doesn't feel like it's about me.
我要去冲个澡
I'm gonna hop in the shower.
什么
What?
你最近怎么了
What's been going on with you lately?
看起来很帅哦
You look so handsome.
谢谢  亲爱的
Oh, well, thank you, sweetie.
你知道吗
You know what,
我的护肤流程又多了一项精华
I added a serum step to my skin-care regimen.
等等
W-Wait a minute.
你就是想拐我们让你去上骑马课
You're just angling for horseback-riding lessons,
对不对
aren't you?
-拜托  -不行
Come on! ‭No.
不能让你变成那种日程满满当当的小孩
You're not gonna become one of those over-scheduled kids
13岁就过度劳累
that burns out at 13
还穿军靴去沙滩
and wears combat boots to the beach.
我是我们学校里最闲的亚洲小孩了
I'm the least-busy Asian kid in my school.
很好  拉住床单另一头
Great. Take the other end of this sheet
帮我给莱昂内尔铺床
and help me make up the bed for Lionel.
莱昂内尔今晚要住这里吗
Lionel's staying here tonight?
对  胡娇和罗纳多会送他过来
Yes. ‭Yes. Pepper and Ronaldo are dropping him off.
去年  胡娇和罗纳多告诉我们
Last year, Pepper and Ronaldo told us
他们想为人父母
that they wanted to become parents
而且正在努力搞到蕾哈娜的卵子
and were on a quest to acquire Rihanna's eggs.
我们说  "你们这俩富婆
And we said, "Or, you rich queens,
也可以给需要家庭的孩子一个家啊"
you could provide a home for a child that needs one."
所以他们领养了一个
So they adopted,
我们有点担心事情发展的情况
and we are a little nervous about how it's going
因为当他们头一回介绍莱昂内尔的时候
because, um, when they first introduced us to Lionel,
我们看得出来他们不是很合
we could tell that it wasn't a great fit.
莱昂内尔  很高兴认识你啊
Hi, Lionel, it's nice meeting you.
3个月前
衣服挺酷
Hey. ‭Cool shirt.
是篮球变装服
It's a basketball costume.
是运动衫
Jersey.
是运动衫  对
Jersey. Right.
《泽西男孩》是一档音乐剧
其中泽西与运动衫同词
就像《泽西男孩》
Like "Jersey Boys."
好了  谁给我杯喝的吧
Okay, somebody fix me a drink.
我们刚从车窗外买了芝士汉堡
We just got cheeseburgers out of a window
还坐在车里吃了
and ate in our car.
我们卖车时需要坦白受过这灾害吗
Do we have to disclose that when we sell it?
虽然一开始不太顺利
It seemed like a bit of a rocky start,
但胡娇说现在还挺不错的
but Pepper said it's going well.
看来做父母确实会改变你
Parenting does change you.
有莉莉之前  我有时候会很戏精
You know, before Lily, I could be so dramatic.
-而我以前总是紧张过度  -但看看我们现在
- Oh, and I used to be so uptight. - But look at us now.
-抱歉  -你的手差点儿伸到我嘴里了
- Oh, sorry. - Okay, your hand almost went in my mouth.
快进来
Come in, come in.
我好喜欢这个
Ohh! I like this!
这样比以前在这里的东西好看多了
It's a lot better than what was here before.
那里以前是我们的厨房
Uh, our kitchen was there before.
我刚才说的不够清楚吗
Am I being unclear?
莱昂内尔  你好时髦啊
Okay, well, Lionel, don't you look sharp?
是伦敦哈罗德买的巴宝莉  对吧
It's Burberry from Harrods in London. Right?
你这孩子太棒了
Ohh, you wonderful child.
你很快就再也不需要那些名牌学习卡了
You won't need those flashcards much longer.
给  莱昂内尔住这里用的
Here, for Lionel's stay --
一些小零食  洗漱用品
some snacks, toiletries,
还有一本设计杂志  你们俩也可以读读
a design magazine you two could also flip through.
好了  莱昂内尔
Okay, so, Lionel, uh,
我们给你在小房间里铺好床了
we have you set up here in the den.
电视也在那里
That's where the TV is,
小卡说我们家有订体育频道呢
and Cam tells me that we have a sports package.
没关系
That's okay.
我得练习写草书了
I should practice my cursive.
胡娇说书法是一门失传的艺术
Pepper says penmanship is a lost art.
是的  就跟感谢信一样要失传了
Yes. As are thank-you notes,
所以我们只能猜测
which is why we can only assume
你们很喜欢我们送的周年礼物
you enjoyed our anniversary gift.
总之  我们得去机场了
Anyway, we have to get to the airport.
再见怎么说呢  莱昂内尔
How do we say goodbye, Lionel?
再会[法语]
Au revoir.
送我们去门口吧
Come walk us to the door.
他们把他怎么了
What have they done to him?
把他变成了小"黑胡娇"
Turned him into a little black Pepper.
太气人了
It's so infuriating.
感觉她都没把你当个男人对待
She treats you like you're not even a man.
你不生气吗
Doesn't that bother you?
如果你讨好每个人
You know, if you please everyone,
你就没有取得足够的进步
you're not making enough progress.
雪莉·桑德伯格名言
Cheryl Sandberg.
美国精英女企业家
此名言来自她鼓励女人追求目标的书籍《向前一步》
这是垃圾吗
Hey, is this garbage?
我不知道  里面有什么
I don't know. What's in it?
"激情情趣绘画工具"
Uh, "Passion Painting Erotic Art Kit"?
那是什么
What is that?
-天啊  -天啊
- Oh, my God. - Oh, my God.
太恶心了
Gross! Ugh! ‭Uh.
其实呢
You know what?
如果她想把你当个小孩来贬低
If she wants to belittle you like you're some child,
我们就用这个
we are going to use this
让她瞧瞧你有多男人
to show her what kind of man you are.
我不想我的T恤和袜子沾上颜料啊
I don't want to get paint on my T-shirt and socks.
那可能这次你得都脱掉了
Well, maybe you'll just have to take them off for this one.
早上好  怎么样啊  兄弟
Morning! How's my guy?
糟透了  我昨晚做了无数噩梦
Awful. I had a zillion nightmares.
我是和小短讲话  不过  你是挺惨啊
I was talking to Shorty, but gee, that's rough.
咱们一块去我的俱乐部吃早餐吧
Hey, let's have breakfast at my club today.
我们每周五会做一个"昨日土豆"
We do a thing on Friday called "Yesterday's Potatoes."
他们把前一天晚的炸薯条
They take last night's French fries
做成今天的家常土豆
and make 'em into today's home fries,
而前一晚的薯条超好吃啊
and last night's fries were fantastic.
听起来不错  但歌洛莉亚已经做好了
Sounds delicious, but, uh, Gloria already cooked.
俩荷包蛋  西班牙辣香肠
Two poached eggs, chorizo,
还有抹黑莓酱的牛角包
and a croissant with blackberry jam.
-赞啊  -曼尼最喜欢的早饭
- Yes! - ‭Manny's favorite.
天啊  你干嘛不直接给他打电话
Geez, why don't you just call him?
顺着习惯就做了的
I made it out of habit.
但幸好  小短喜欢
But thankfully, Shorty loved it.
是吧  亲爱的
Didn't you, Papi?
好吧  听我说
Okay, I'll tell you what.
你干嘛不换下那睡衣
Why don't you get out of those pajamas...
什么睡衣
What pajamas?
来坐  那不是睡衣吗
come sit while I -- Those aren't pajamas?
不是  其实呢  歌洛莉亚和我送乔上学后
No. Actually, Gloria and I are gonna go to the farmer's market
-打算去农贸市场  -为什么
- after we drop Joe off at school. - ‭Why?
算是跟我工作有关吧
It's kind of work-related.
你的朋友有着成功的果汁生意呢
Your friend has a very successful juice business
在哥斯达黎加
in Costa Rica.
他们称我水果之王[骚基之王]
They call me the Fruit King.
他们肯定是看到你的衣服了  听我说
They must have seen the outfit. I'll tell you what.
我今天早上办公室还有点事
I got a little thing this morning at the office.
我们1:00在这儿见
Why don't we meet back here at 1:00
咱俩好朋友好好聊聊  好吗
for a little best-friend catch-up? Deal?
好的  听起来不错
Deal. Sounds good.
知道什么听起来不怎么样吗
You know what doesn't sound good?
一个爷们叫另一个爷们为最好的朋友
One grown man calling another grown man his best friend.
她不懂我们  回见  老兄
She doesn't get us. See you, buddy.
那是什么
What is that?
白面包加毛豆泥
Crostini with edamame puree.
胡娇说还在吃西红柿罗勒的人
Pepper says anyone who's still doing tomato-basil
错过了流行[船]  或者说活该错过
missed the boat, or should have.
莱昂内尔  你不一定要吃
Hey, Lionel, you don't have to eat
他们给你带来的东西
that stuff they brought for you.
我们不会告密的
We -- we won't tell.
来个奇多  尽情做个小孩
Ch-- Pop a Cheeto. Be a kid.
但他俩费心
But the guys went to the trouble
让罗莎给我做了这个
of making Rosa make this for me.
我应该吃完它
I should finish it.
莱昂内尔  当心  接着
Hey, Lionel, heads up. Catch.
不了  谢谢
No, thank you.
胡娇和罗纳多不让在家里玩球
Pepper and Ronaldo don't allow ball play in the house.
你不在胡娇和罗纳多家里
Well, you aren't at Pepper and Ronaldo's house.
这里是好玩之家
This is a fun house.
是啊  他们也这么叫
Yeah, that's what they call it.
现在我真的想扔东西了
Well, now I feel like throwing something,
莱昂内尔  注意啦  接着
so, hey, Lionel, heads up. Catch.
对不起
Uh, I'm sorry.
我和胡娇说了  穿这外套我胳膊动不了
I told Pepper I couldn't move my arms in this jacket,
但他说  "修身胜过合身"
but he said, "Fit over function."
不  没事  没事
No, you know what? I-It's fine. It's fine.
-东西碎了没什么  -我来赔
- Things break. - I'll pay for it.
不  你不用  那是我们在加油站
No, you won't. We got it for free
开信用卡时免费送的
when we opened a credit card at the gas station.
我坚持赔  我包里有旅行支票
I insist. I have traveler's checks in my bag.
不  莱昂内尔  没事的
No, Lionel, it's f-- okay.
不  这让我很难受
No, you know what, this is upsetting me.
他穿也受他们控制
He dresses the way they tell him to dress.
吃也受他们控制
He eats what they tell him to eat.
是啊  他们控制了他的一言一行
I know. They control his every move,
也很明显能看出他为了配合压力很大
and he clearly feels pressured to go along with it.
或许这就是为什么他一直对我说
That's probably why he keeps telling me
我能住在这很幸运
how lucky I am to live here.
他说了这种话吗  你怎么不告诉我们
He said that? Wh-Why didn't you tell us?
你们俩说话时不太给别人插话的余...
You guys don't leave a lot of space to jump into your conversat-
你知道这是怎么回事吗  小卡
You know what this is, Cam?
他明显很嫉妒莉莉
He's obviously jealous of Lily
因为我们允许她做个孩子  能尽情玩耍
because we allow her to be a kid and have fun.
如果他知道我能去学骑马
Imagine how jealous he'll be
想象一下他该有多嫉妒啊
when he finds out about my horseback-riding lessons.
-放弃吧  -想得美
- Let it go. - We're not doing that.
你知道我现在想吃什么吗
You know what I'm in the mood for?
我知道听起来很神经  但我想吃华夫饼
And I know it sounds crazy, but waffles.
什么鬼
What the hell?
你说得对  你总能阻止我浪过头
You're right. You keep me from flying too high.
"提前祝你生日快乐  妈妈
"Happy early birthday, Mom.
爱你的艾丽克斯和本"  我的天啊
Love, Alex and Ben." Oh, my God.
对啊  还有六个月才到你生日呢
I know. Your birthday isn't for six months.
不  菲尔
No, Phil!
二位好  这画挺酷的  谁画的
Hey, guys. Cool painting. Who did it?
艾丽克斯和本
‭Alex and Ben.
我昨晚好像听到他们作画了
Oh, I think I heard them making it last night.
她一直说他"做"得不对  但我看挺好的
She kept saying he was doing it wrong, but it looks good to me.
虽然我对艺术毫无了解
I mean, I don't know anything about art,
但  我了解自己喜欢什么
but... I know what I like.
我不过调侃一句本是妈宝
I make one comment about Ben's mommy,
艾丽克斯就来这一出
and Alex does this.
她太好斗了
It's aggressive.
感觉她用掌印画火鸡才多久之前
I remember when she made a turkey with her handprint.
她只是想气我
She's just trying to get
看我什么反应  对不对
some sort of reaction out of me, isn't she?
但你不会上钩的  对吧
But you're not gonna take the bait, right?
-你没那么小气  -我可说不好  菲尔
- You're bigger than that. ‭- I don't know, Phil.
她这可是对我们大不敬
This is-This is very disrespectful.
我觉得我们得挫挫她的锐气
I think she needs to be taken down a peg.
你打算坐下和她好好聊聊  对吧
So then, you'll just sit her down and talk to her, right?
那也行
I could do that,
或许在她和本过来一起吃晚餐时说
maybe over dinner with her and Ben...
这就对了  我为你骄傲
There you go. I'm proud of you.
一顿令人难忘的晚餐
...A dinner no one will soon forget.
好吧
Fine.
但我告诉你  我要去吃华夫饼了
But know that I'm having a waffle.
瞧瞧你对我们家做了些什么
This is what you're doing to our family!
停车  你知道规矩  戴好头盔
Stop. You know the rules. Helmet.
继续开吧
Off with you.
小短  你在说笑
Shorty, you're kidding.
我从不拿水果的事说笑
I never joke when it comes to fruit.
你手里的奇迹之果是李子和杏杂交的
That miracle in your hand is a half plum, half apricot.
想当初只有一起打成果汁才能让二者结合
There was a time they could only accomplish that in juice.
杰
Oh. ‭Jay.
不好意思  我一高兴忘记时间了
Oh, sorry, I kind of lost track of time.
别在意
Hey, no worries.
我不过是你四年没见的最好的朋友
Who among us hasn't blown off his best friend
小短是在第5季第13集离开的
你为了买水果放我鸽子也是人之常情
he hasn't seen in four years to go fruit shopping?
感觉某人该来杯石榴葡萄大爆炸降降火
Sounds like somebody could use a Pomegrapefruit Blast.
"大爆炸"就是"酸奶"
Blast means "yogurt."
你在丛林里住得太久了
You've been spending too much time in the jungle.
你需要重新体验一下文明
What you need is a little civilization.
我们去打保龄球吧
Let's go bowling.
我很想去  不过...
Well, I would love to, but, uh...
我想在去剧院前睡一会儿
I kind of want to take a nap before we got to the theater.
-你要带小短去剧院吗  -是的
- Um, you're taking Shorty to the theater? - Ah, yes.
我买票本是想和曼尼一起去
I got the tickets for me and Manny,
但他不能去
but he can't go
小短又很喜欢《魔法坏女巫》
and Shorty loves "Wicked."
又名《女巫前传》  是知名音乐剧
讲述《绿野仙踪》里那位坏女巫的故事
他觉得他像好女巫格琳达
He thinks he's a Galinda
他哥像坏女巫爱尔法巴
and his brother an Elphaba.
你意识到自己在做什么了吗
You know what you're doing, don't you?
你在把小短变成曼尼
You're turning Shorty into Manny.
别再霸占我最好的朋友了
Stop hogging my best friend!
好吧  如果你不爽  那你带他去
Okay, if you're so upset, then you can take him.
但别再说"最好的朋友"了
But stop saying "best friend."
你这个年纪不该用那个词了
You're too old to be using that word.
麦莉·赛勒斯主演的青少年喜剧《汉娜·蒙塔娜》
蒙大拿的汉娜可以有最好的朋友
Hannah from Montana has a best friend.
而你不可以
You don't.
至少我最好的朋友不是我儿子
At least my best friend isn't my son.
我是你最好的朋友吗  妈妈
I'm your best friend, Mom?
是的  宝贝
Yes, Papi.
你就是他刚才说的那个儿子
You are the son that he's talking about.
如果他说莉莉能在我们家很幸运
Look, if he said Lily's lucky to be here,
那他显然在胡娇和罗纳多家过得不开心
then he's clearly unhappy at Pepper and Ronaldo's.
哪个孩子会开心啊
I mean, w-what kid wouldn't be?
他们家得维持那么一尘不染
I mean, that house is so sterile.
你记不记得那次胡娇生我气时
Do you remember when Pepper got mad at me
他先铺好塑料布
and he laid down plastic
才朝我脸上泼饮料
before throwing a drink in my face?
那我们必须得去说点什么吧
So then, we have to say something.
我们大家是朋友
‭I mean, we're their friends.
我们为人父母又比较有经验
We're experienced parents.
他们现在改还来得及啊
There's -- There's still time for them to change.
别  我们没资格管
No, it's not our place.
我们就...  别管人家家务事吧
Let's just, you know, stay out of it.
他们都不锁门吗
They keep their door unlocked?
这就是家里没什么东西可偷的好处
That's the upside of not having anything worth stealing.
你们是糟糕的父母
You're terrible parents.
好吧  看来我们还是要说
Okay, so, I guess we are saying something.
好了
All right.
是时候来点严厉的教育[激烈的爱]了
Time for some tough love, boys.
天啊  我们就害怕
Oh, goodness, we feared you two
你们俩喜欢那种"玩法"
might be into that sort of thing,
但我们还是免了吧
but we're gonna have to pass.
我才不信你真觉得他是这意思
Oh, you can't possibly think that's what he meant.
不  我在转移话题
No, I'm deflecting!
我感受到残酷坦诚的恶心威胁
I feel the sickening threat of brutal honesty,
我极其不舒服
and I'm wildly uncomfortable.
好吧  要开始了
Okay, well, here goes.
我们觉得你们收养莱昂内尔很好  但是...
We think it's great that you adopted Lionel, but...
好吧  这反应也太早了
Okay, a little early for that reaction.
我还没说到
I haven't even gotten to say,
"别把你们的花里胡哨强加到可怜的孩子身上"
"Stop imposing your fancy ways on that poor child."
可以反应了
And hit it.
我们做父母
Look, we have been at this parenting thing
也有一段时间了  而...
for a while now, and...
是啊  莉莉最"讨人喜欢"了
Yeah, and Lily is such a delight!
对不起  我可能会有点抬杠
Sorry, I'm gonna be lashing out for a bit.
总之  为人父母有时候
Anyway, um, part of parenting
就是要让孩子接触到你重视的东西
is exposing your children to things that you value.
比方说艺术  文化和好的食物...
You know, art and culture and good food...
我们就是这么做的
That's exactly what we're doing.
但有时候还要让他们发掘自我
But it's also about letting them figure out who they are,
做他们自己想做的事
doing things that they want to do
即使你们不喜欢
even though you don't like 'em.
他是个孩子
Yeah, he's a kid.
他不会想睡觉听歌剧和在鸡蛋里加鱼子酱
He doesn't want opera at bedtime and caviar on his eggs.
他...他想要玩球和吃奇多
He -- He wants to play ball and eat Cheetos.
我确实看见他把生鱼片吐到了餐巾上
Well, I did see him spit some sashimi into a napkin,
但我当时希望他只是在担心自己的体重
but I hoped he was just worried about his weight.
这样吧  我们出去
You know what, let's get outside.
我们做点开心的事  让莱昂内尔知道
Let's go do something fun and show Lionel
在你们面前做个孩子也没关系
that it -- that it's okay to be a kid with you guys.
你们觉得怎么样
What do you say?
-拿吧 -没关系
- Get in there. - It's fine.
这是用什么奶酪厂的...
And from what fromagerie...
-你就是个德州小城市人  -你个混蛋
- You're from Lubbock, Texas. - You son of a bitch!
没想到没人跟我说过
Oh, I can't believe no one told me
足垒球是在草上玩的
kickball is performed on grass.
在公园里演出的莎士比亚我都看不下去了
I can barely stand Shakespeare in a park.
这对你们族群可不太好
This is not great for your people.
好了  莱昂内尔  来个全垒打吧
Okay, Lionel, bring me home.
你可以的
You got this.
好的  先生
Yes, I do, sir.
好
All right.
太棒了
Yeah!
-天啊  发生什么了  -打他
- Oh, my God, what is happening? - Hit him!
胡娇  打他
Pepper, hit him! Oh!
打小卡
Hit Cam!
我的...
Oh, my --!
我才不信你真觉得他是这意思
You can't possibly think that's what he meant.
给我
Oh! ‭Give me that.
-给我  -好
- Give me that. - Okay.
我一开始也心里打鼓
I was skeptical at first
毕竟橙子过时很久了
because orange is so over right now,
但我很喜欢
but I love it.
你喜欢吗  胡娇
You like it, too, Pepper?
太好吃了
Mm, wonderful.
我上一次见到那么多人工色素[颜色]
I haven't seen this much artificial color
是《北非谍影》被修复成彩色版那会儿
since Ted Turner got his hands on "Casablanca."
该知名杰出电影最早是黑白电影
被修复成彩色版后  许多影迷十分嫌弃
你爷爷奶奶是在拖车里长大的
Your grandparents grew up in a trailer.
我恨你
I hate you.
好了  下一个到谁了
All right, who's up next?
-胡娇  -胡娇
- Pepper! ‭- Pepper!
足垒球有多少幕
Oh. How many scenes does kickball have?
你可以的  胡娇儿
You can do it, Peppercito!
记住  就像跳舞一样
Remember, it's just like dancing.
跳舞
Dancing.
五  六  七  八  踢
And five, six, seven, eight, kick!
胡娇
Oh! ‭Pepper!
我受伤了
Ohh! Oh, I'm hurt!
疼死我了
I'm really hurt!
如果你们两个有钱的话  我会告死你们
Oh, if you two had any money, I'd sue you.
我亲爱的  没关系
Mi amor, it's okay.
有关系
It's not okay.
我在荒野曝晒  像个帮厨一样大汗淋漓
I'm out in the wild, schvitzing like a line cook.
一波接一波地被羞辱
It's one humiliation after the next!
莱昂内尔  亲爱的  我想要成为你要的父亲
Lionel, sweetheart, I want to be the father you need,
但这不是我
but this is not me.
我讨厌运动和大自然  还有
I hate sports and nature and --
还有果汁牛奶冻
and sherbet --
老天  我真讨厌果汁牛奶冻
God, do I hate sherbet!
世上只有冰淇淋和雪芭  没有中间的了
There's ice cream and sorbet and nothing in between.
果汁牛奶冻由果汁和乳制品制成
雪芭由新鲜果汁和糖制成  不含乳制品
其实呢  我对篮球没兴趣
Just so you know, I don't care about kickball
或冰棒  或任何那一类的东西
or Popsicles or any of that stuff.
我喜欢我们的生活方式
I like how we live.
真的吗
You do?
莱昂内尔  不用因为压力而说违心的话
Lionel, don't feel pressured to say that if you don't mean it.
是真的
I mean it.
我喜欢书房里的西洋双陆棋  法国产的芝士
Backgammon in the study, cheese from France,
而不是戴着太阳眼镜的豹子
not a cheetah in sunglasses.
莱昂内尔  我的心都要被你融化了
Lionel, you're melting my heart.
我也是  你这个完美的孩子
Mine, too, you perfect boy.
你们怎么会觉得我不喜欢我们的生活
What made you think I didn't like our life?
是这样的
Well, now, see... ‭
他们强迫你
They were forcing you to,
-我们以为...  -我们觉得...
- and it just seemed to us... - It seemed to us...
你跟莉莉说她和我们住在一起很幸运
You told Lily that she was lucky to live with us.
-记得吗  -我是想让她心里好受一点
- Remember? - I was trying to make her feel better.
我拥有如此多  而她...
I got so much, and she got...
她的头发是他们在家剪的
They give her haircuts at home.
我可是上过培训课的
Okay, I took a class.
他们连骑马课都不让她去上
They wouldn't even let her take horseback-riding lessons.
-因为很危险  -因为很危险
- Because it's dangerous. - Because it's dangerous.
还是因为你们懒得早上7点载我大老远去上课
Or is it because you have to drive me across town at 7:00 A.M.?
优秀的家长
I thought good parents
不是应该满足孩子的愿望吗
were supposed to do things their kids want to do?
好吧  但也不是不危险
Okay, well, it's not not dangerous,
而且她还太小  所以...
and she's also too young, so...
小卡  算了  罪证确凿
Cam, come on. The jig's up.
没错  莉莉  我们太自私了
Yes, Lily, we were -- we were being selfish, okay?
你可以去上课
You can have your lessons.
谢谢
Thank you.
我能不能跟她一起上骑马课
Can I take horseback-riding lessons with her, too?
你想要什么都行
Anything you want.
你们可以顺路来我们家接上他
You can swing by and pick him up on your way.
我回来了
Hey, there.
老公  你怎么样啊
Hi, honey. How are you?
挺好的
Good.
你看上去没那么可怕了
Well, you seem less scary. ‭
这是不是代表我们会跟女儿和她男友
Does this mean we're gonna have a nice, pleasant dinner
共进一顿友好愉快的晚餐了
with our daughter and her boyfriend?
对我有点信心好吗
Hey, give me a little credit.
我忙了一整天
I worked so hard all day
就为了确保我把一切都准备好了
just to make sure I got everything ready.
不是吧
Oh, come on!
你一定是在逗我呢吧
You have got to be kidding me.
"极速画框公司"果然不负盛名
Well, it turns out Speedy Frame really lives up to its name.
我们来了
We're here!
克莱尔  我给你带了一瓶加州葡...  不
Claire, I got you a bottle of pi-- No!
太好了  你收到我们送的礼物
Oh, good, you got our gift.
你送给他们了吗
You gave it to them?
别慌  宝宝  她想要的正是这个
Don't freak out, babe. That's exactly what she wants.
妈妈  挂在那儿我真喜欢
Wow, Mom, I really love it there.
我也是
Me, too.
性爱画作挂到墙上说明艾丽克丝成功攻入她心
Sex painting on the wall means Alex was in her head.
而我攻进来就打算闹一阵子才走
And I wasn't planning on leaving anytime soon.
我不知道怎么会摆出这种手势
I don't know where that came from.
再来点豆角吗
More green beans?
好啊  我就不客气了
Oh, yes. Don't mind if I do.
我得承认  我感觉有点怪怪的
I have to admit, I feel slightly uncomfortable.
时候不早了
Well, it's getting late.
才七点半
It's 7:30.
爸爸  工作怎么样了
So, Dad, how's work?
不  我们不会坐在这里装没事
No. We're not gonna sit here and pretend.
我们要谈谈那幅画
We're going to talk about this.
你爸爸说得对
Your father's right.
我看到那幅画时  就觉得...
When I saw that painting, I thought...
你太克制自己了
you're too restrained.
-你们得放纵一点  -我要谈的不是这个
- You two need to loosen up a little. - That's not what I meant.
不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
我感激你的建议  而且这问题很容易解决
I appreciate the advice, and that should be an easy fix
毕竟我现在有一个"精"力充沛的伴侣
now that I've come into my own with such a virile partner.
天啊
Oh, my God.
够了
Okay, that is enough!
瞧你对这个可怜的男子做了什么
Look what you're doing to this poor man,
让他夹在你们俩之间扭曲变态的
putting him in the middle of this twisted power struggle
权力斗争中
between the two of you!
这正是你和你爸整天对我做的事
This is exactly what you and your dad always did to me.
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
我第一次见你爸的时候
The first time I met your dad,
他不认可我  你就一直亲我
who did not approve me, you kept kissing me.
还有我们第一次和你家人
Or the first time we went away with your family
去小木屋度假时  你故意各种呻吟
to that cabin and you made all those noises.
我呻吟不是为了气他
Th-That wasn't about that.
那如今这些呻吟都到哪儿去了  克莱尔
Then where did those noises go, Claire?
我不会束手旁观看着你手撕本
I will not stand here while you tear poor Ben down
就像你爸当年也手撕了我一样
the way that Jay tore me down,
还有  本  你是蓝色还是金色
and, Ben, were you blue or gold?
-我必须得知道  -我是蓝色
- I need to know. - I was blue.
我想要来点《阿凡达》的感觉
I wanted to feel like an Avatar.
知名电影  剧中部分角色全身蓝色
本  是我不对
Ben, I'm sorry.
菲尔跟艾丽克斯说得对
Phil and Alex are right.
你不应该被如此对待
You don't deserve to be treated this way.
谢谢  克莱尔  其实我...
Thank you, Claire. You know, I --
我还没说完  我对你做的事
Not finished. I am doing to you...
就是当年我爸对我与菲尔做的事
...exactly what my father did to me and Phil.
他觉得任何人都配不上他的宝贝女儿...
No one was good enough for his little girl, and...
我想我也觉得没人配得上我的宝贝女儿
And I suppose nobody's good enough for mine.
但亲爱的  我也曾站在你这立场
But, honey, I've been where you are right now,
所以我是最不应该
and I'm the last person
给你增添无数磨难的人
who should be making it harder for you.
我真的很对不起
I'm...I'm so sorry.
我不该故意留下性爱画作给你们看
And I'm sorry I left the sex painting for you to find.
不知道你听完会不会开心点
If it makes you feel any better,
其实画是假的
we faked it.
本吓死了  根本无法"表现"
Ben was so freaked out, he couldn't perform.
我听了一点都没开心啊
Doesn't make me feel any better.
但我开心多了
That helps a lot.
《魔法坏女巫》
♪ 我相信自己已变得比以前更好 ♪
♪ I do believe I have been changed for the better ♪
我还是没懂为什么她是绿色的
I still don't understand why she's green.
这首是好女巫与坏女巫对唱的歌曲《For Good》
坏女巫小时候喝了魔酒  变成绿皮肤
♪ 因为我认识了你 ♪
♪ Because I knew you ♪
♪ 让我永远地... ♪
♪ I have been changed ♪
她们以前曾关系那么好
They used to be so close.
-你还好吧  -♪ 改变了自己 ♪
- You okay? - ♪ For good ♪
-她们怎么变成这样了  -我不知道啊
- What happened to them? - I don't know.
一个金发碧眼的万人迷  一个绿皮肤的"怪物"
从竞争对手变成至交  最后却因为立场不同成为敌人
我中间睡着了几分钟
I-I dozed off for a couple of minutes.
不好意思  借过一下
Excuse me. Excuse me.
对不起  不好意思
I'm sorry. Excuse me.
靠
Damn it.
早知道就该让歌洛莉亚来
I should've sent Gloria.
兄弟
Hey, fella.
你这是怎么了
What happened in there?
杰  我是个骗子
I'm a fraud, Jay.
我就是个大骗子
I'm a damn fraud.
别这样啦  人人都有怪异的哭点
Come on. We all cry at weird stuff.
像我是拳击手打完之后拥抱的那一刻
For me, it's when boxers hug after a fight.
我的重点不是哭
It's not the crying I'm worried about.
其实你说得没错
You were right.
你说过我要是去哥斯达黎加  就会倾家荡产
You said I would lose everything if I went to Costa Rica,
你说对了
and I did.
你在说什么鬼
What are you talking about?
你不是什么果汁业大亨吗
I-I-I thought you were a big juice magnate.
谎话  都是谎话
Lies! It's all lies, Jay!
我才不是什么果汁大亨
I'm not no juice magnate.
我开了个果汁小摊  本来一切顺利
I had a juice stand, and things were okay --
直到后来猴子拿到了我的刀...
until these monkeys got a hold of my knives.
律师说我不能谈这件事
The lawyer says I can't talk about it.
达琳也跟高空滑索的老板好上
Then Darlene takes off with this honcho in zip lines
然后离我而去
and leaves me.
所以我才一直躲着你
That's why I've been avoiding you.
我就是个丢人现眼的废物
I'm a disgusting loser!
你把我当什么人了
Who are you talking to?
在我面前你怕什么丢人
You don't need to be embarrassed.
但你说过"你到时候出事了
But you said, "Don't come crying to me
可别来找我哭  还要我帮你收拾烂摊子"
when it all turns to hell and I have to pick up the pieces."
-你说的  -也就是说说而已嘛
- You said that! - ‭It's just what you say.
我当然会帮忙你收拾残局啊
Of course I'm gonna pick up the pieces.
不然我还能怎么样
What else would I do?
你是我最好的朋友啊
You're my best friend.
妈的  你也是我最好的朋友啊  要抱抱
And you're my best friend, damn it. Come on.
因为认识你  我变得更好了
I'm better because I knew you.
一辈子当最好的好朋友
Best friends forever.
歌洛莉亚说得对  我现在懂了
Yeah, Gloria's right. I...I hear it now.
曼尼开门嘛
Manny open the door.
我知道你在房里
I know you are in there.
妈  你来做什么
Mom, what are you doing here.
我知道你说过你想有自己的空间
I know that you said that you want your space,
但对我来说真的很难熬
but it's so hard on me, ok?
所以我要你每天睡前给我发一封短信
So, I want a text message at the end of everyday,
跟我报平安
telling me you are ok.
然后每周三次
And three times a week,
发你的自拍给我
a picture of your face
这样我才能看着你的眼睛
so I can look into your eyes
知道你有没有说谎骗我
and see if you are lying to me.
妈  我们昨天早上才互通过短信
Mother, we texted yesterday morning.
才没有呢  上次都多久之前了
No, we didn't. That was days ago.
昨天早上8点37分
Yesterday at 8:37A.M.
你问我收到你寄的补给包了没
You asked if I got your care package,
还让我别告诉杰你给我寄了香肠
and said don't tell Jay I gave you a sausage.
然后你不小心发了语音消息
Then you accidentally hit voice memo,
我听到你叫斯黛拉找块地去死
and I heard you tell Stella to go in a yard and die.
对不起嘛  我好想你
Sorry. I just miss you.
你偶尔来看看我应该也没关系啦
I guess it's not so terrible of you stopping by every now and then.